Charles, this is exciting.
- Medal of valor.
- I know.
For getting shot
in the butt.
Oh, my butt!
For exceptional acts
of heroism
or voluntary risk
of personal safety.
But, you know, six of one.
This is one of
the NYPD's highest honors.
Today is your day,
Detective Boyle.
Heroism can't be
measured by a piece of metal.
But what else can we do
to recognize
the brave officers
that have put their
lives on the line?
It is my great honor to present
the medal of valor
to Detective
Charles Boyle...
And sergeant
peanut butter.
Oh, my God.
Charles is getting
the same medal as a horse.
At least Boyle
was announced first.
Because the horse
outranks him.
This is amazing.
That's enough, Peralta.
This is a huge honor,
and nothing can take that
away from him.
The horse is pooping
on the stage.
Sergeant peanut butter
is pooping on the stage.
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.addic7ed.com/
Peralta.
Santiago.
The bet ends today.
Are you ready?
I was born ready.
To lose?
The whole question was,
"are you ready to lose?"
And you said
you were born that way.
Twist my words
all you want.
Okay.
I'm winning this bet.
- No.
-  What bet?
What are you guys
talking about?
Seriously?
The bet?
They've been keeping score
all year.
It comes up
all the time.
What are you doing
all day?
Nothing.
Why, you wanna hang out?
A year ago today,
Peralta and I made a bet
to prove who's
a better Detective.
Whoever makes more
felony arrests, wins.
What are the stakes?
And don't say money,
because I know you're in debt.
If you really knew
anything about me,
you would've said
"crushing debt,"
and I'll bet whatever,
'cause there's no way
I'm losing.
What about your car?
Oh!
That thing
is a date magnet.
I mean, how many girls have you
made out with in that car?
Six?
Well, I'm gonna win, so sure.
Let's bet the car.
Yes.
No, Jakey, no!
That car
is your superpower.
Thor would never
wager his hammer.
Neil Patrick Harris would never
wager his showmanship.
Losing that car will be
the worst thing
in the world for you.
Well, what's
the worst thing
in the world for you,
Santiago?
Being one of those girls
in Jake's car.
Okay, okay, okay.
Then it is settled.
If Peralta loses,
Santiago gets his car.
If Santiago loses, she goes
for a date in said car.
Game on.
Wow, your handshake
is quite firm.
I took a seminar.
Where?
And the score
is all tied up.
But not for long.
For in eight hours,
I will win the bet
and take Santiago
on the worst date
in the history
of the world.
Attention.
After today's shift,
I'd like everyone
join me at the bar
for drinks
in honor of Detective Boyle
and his medal of valor.
Oh, my God, is peanut butter
gonna be there?
That horse is a damn hero.
Peanut butter
will not be joining us.
He's being feted
by the united nations.
As you were.
Pen.
You... ow!
Rolly chair!
Gina's desk!
Oh, Jake.
No!
Captain, hey.
You're looking
stoic today,
like a wise old oak.
I'm not gonna give you
more cases
so you can win your bet
with Santiago.
What?
Oh, right, the bet.
Totally forgot
about that.
Well, granted,
this friendly competition
has led to you and Santiago
putting in more hours
and arresting more perps,
especially this last week.
Up by one, Peralta.
Anything you want to say
to your car
before you never
see it again? Hmm?
Hey, Santiago, do you have
any dietary restrictions
that medieval times
should know about?
Yes, 3-1-1?
What's the safest way
to set a car on fire?
Ooh. Hmm!
Both of you have done
exemplary work,
which I appreciate.
And I can see that by
the absolutely no indicators
on your face.
However,
you are colleagues,
and the fallout from this bet
has the potential
to put a strain on your
professional relationship.
Only if I lose.
I'm a terrible sport.
Cases will be assigned
as they usually are.
Dismissed.
Captain, you look...
No.
Rosa, hey,
would you like to share
a cup of coffee with me?
I got some gorgeous
new coffee beans.
Sure,
that sounds great.
Isn't that, like, your fifth
cup of coffee today?
I'm trying
to counteract
the drowsiness
from my pain meds.
I took
a double dose
after the incident
at the ceremony.
Bring peanut
butter forward... forward.
Uh, can the little guy
take a big step back, please?
My name
is Charles Boyle.
I won the same medal
as this horse.
The footage from my fall
led the local news,
so who's the hero now,
peanut butter?
Peanut butter.
Gina, you're just
trying to hurt me
to distract yourself
from your own internal pain.
Also, you should use
less conditioner,
because this
is a flat mess.
What's going on with Boyle?
His pain meds
are making him weird.
Oh, okay.
Yes.
This happened to my dad
when he got
his vasectomy un-reversed.
You get all relaxed
and you have no filter
and you just start dropping
truth bombs on everyone.
Oh, that explains
the elevator.
I'm worried you don't
find me interesting.
I'm gonna pretend
someone texted me.
Bloop.
Gina, please keep an eye
on Boyle today.
He's gonna say something
to the wrong person
and get himself punched.
Sure, I'd love to see
Charles get punched.
Try again?
I will stop Charles
from getting punched.
Correct.
Great.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present Carl Laudson,
who stole $3,000.
Santiago takes the lead
with one minute left.
Suck it, Peralta.
Oh, no.
That's right,
"oh, no."
Oh, no.
You don't seem worried.
Why aren't you worried?
Bring in the Johns.
I ran a prostitution sting
through vice
and arrested 30 guys
for soliciting.
That's not a felony.
It is when
it's your second offense,
which is the case for ten
of these gentlemen.
Four of them
are actually named John.
Ironic.
Anyhoo,
ten more for Peralta.
Accept your fate.
Never.
Five, four, three, two, one.
No.
Jake wins,
Amy loses.
♪ Celebrate
good times come on! ♪
♪ Let's celebrate
Look!
♪ Celebrate good times, come on!
♪ Whoo!
Amy Santiago,
you have made me
the happiest man
on earth.
I spent $1
on this ring.
Will you go on the worst date
ever with me?
You have to say yes.
Yes.
She said yes!
She said yes.
This is for you.
Amy Santiago,
date time.
Time to date.
Peralta, this outfit
is ridiculous.
Chop chop.
There's plenty
of embarrassing to do
and only a few hours
to do it in.
Happy?
Oh, yeah.
You look like every girl
at every bat mitzvah
I ever had a crush on.
Let's see the bow.
Just like
Jenny Gildenhorn.
Why do I wish
you had braces?
Should we get you braces?
No, that's too much.
Here I come.
Nice shorts.
Thank you.
Believe it or not,
they were not
very expensive.
Do I really have to
wear this all night?
You know the rules.
The date starts now
and ends at midnight.
I decide what you wear,
what you eat,
and where we go.
Oh, and there is
one more rule.
No matter
what happens,
you're not allowed
to fall in love with me.
Won't be a problem.
Detective Boyle, I just wanted
to say congratulations.
Your medal
was well-deserved.
Thank you, sir.
Your breath is terrible.
Charles,
can I speak with you?
Hey, where's Rosa?
I haven't seen her
all night.
Did you know my wife
pays me alimony?
Okay, let's take a seat.
I'm gonna keep an eye on
you all night, little buddy.
Okay.
Thanks.
Hey, baby.
Happy you made it.
Captain, I'd like you
to meet my wife, Sharon.
It's so wonderful
to meet you.
I've heard such great things
about you.
And you.
Your husband
is a real hero.
If you ask me,
he should've been up there
with Detective Boyle today.
What for?
For saving my life.
He means metaphorically.
You know, saving him
from all that paperwork.
Paper cuts
are a slow death, baby.
No, I was referring to how
he threw his body
at an emotionally
disturbed criminal
who was trying
to kill me.
Nooo!
He did what?
Are you
back in the field?
Oh.
I have caused a problem.
I think I am...
Getting a text message.
Bloop.
Ah. There it is.
Why is this the first
I'm hearing about this?
I thought I told you.
Remember when you were
half asleep
watching the news
and the babies were quiet,
and I said, real low,
"hey, baby.
I'm back in the field.
You want something to eat?"
And you were like,
"what?"
And I was like,
"you want something to eat?"
And you said, "sure."
And I got you
an oatmeal cookie?
Remember?
You are a piece of work,
Terrance.
Oh, damn.
She called me Terrance.
I'm doomed.
Hot date coming through.
Hey, attention,
everyone.
Now I know that tonight
is Boyle's big night.
But let's forget about that
completely for a moment
and admire and comment on every
terrible aspect of this.
Permission to go
to the bathroom?
Granted.
First of three.
Use them wisely.
Hey.
Congrats again, buddy.
I really am proud of you.
Still wearing the medal,
huh?
Yes, I want women to be
impressed by me.
All right.
Well, I'm sorry
that I can't stay,
but I have a terrible night
planned for Amy.
First up is the mall
photo studio,
where we'll take our official
date portrait.
The picture will
be the two of us
playing one saxophone.
Then some peel-and-eat shrimp
for dinner
at a dangerously cheap
seafood restaurant.
And then I've contracted
a youth choir
to serenade us.
♪ Santiago Santiago
♪ Santiago
♪ Santiago ♪
♪ You suck so bad
Yes!
They'll sing to her
at midnight
the middle
of Times Square.
She and
500 German tourists
will savor that memory
for all times.
Jake, do you know why
little boys
pull little girls' pigtails
on playgrounds?
'Cause they're so easy
to grab.
They're just begging
to be pulled.
Because they
like the girls,
and that's the only way
they know
how to get
their attention.
What are you saying?
All of this teasing,
this elaborate date,
somewhere down deep,
you like Amy.
Like, "like her,"
like her.
Okay, that's
straight-up insanity.
How much did you spend
on tonight?
$1,400, but all of it's
on credit cards,
so it's, like, $5 a month
for the next 2,000 years.
I do not like Amy!
You're putting a lot
of effort into a joke.
Why don't you sit down
and have a real
conversation with her?
Okay, Boyle,
you live in your ex-wife's
new boyfriend's basement.
I'm not taking advice
from you.
Hup.
I'm ashamed
of my living situation.
Rosa, why are you
sequestered
over by this
old cell phone?
I'm avoiding Boyle
and his truth bombs.
I sometimes worry
I'm gonna become you.
He keeps saying
he wants to talk to me.
I'm afraid he's gonna
tell me he loves me
or propose marriage
or something.
Oh, my God.
That makes me kind of
want to cry.
He dove in front
of those bullets for me.
I can't be mean to him.
I watched him
make coffee
for 28 minutes
this morning.
But I also can't
lead him on.
Captain Holt told me not to
let him get hurt tonight.
So I'll keep him
away from you.
Have you seen Rosa?
Rosa died
eight years ago.
Come on.
Let's get you a drink.
Excuse me, everyone.
Santiago and I will be
performing the steerage jig
from the film Titanic,
which we have prepared for
in no way, shape,
or form.
Romantic.
No, embarrassing.
Milady.
You look pretty.
I hate your guts.
Channel that passion
into the dance.
Peralta.
Scully, tag in.
Okay.
Keep spinning.
Yes. One of
our informants just called.
We've been tracking
a crew
that lifts cargo
out of Laguardia.
The C.I. knows
where the trucks unload,
so I need you to stake out
the drop site.
Oh, sir,
I'm right in the middle
of this date
and I cannot reschedule.
I have far, far too many
non-refundable deposits.
I'm renting a tiger cub
by the hour.
For what?
Don't even know.
Waiting for inspiration.
Well, this is not
a negotiation, so go.
All right, fine,
but I'm taking Santiago with me.
As soon as we're done,
it's back to the date.
Darling.
Brief pause.
Duty calls.
Oh, thank God.
Gina, tag in?
No, not even
if it would cure cancer.
Okay.
Look, baby, I'm sorry,
but Captain's life
was in danger.
I just did
what I had to do.
It was
an impulse decision.
Well, I guess
I can understand that.
Sharon.
I have to apologize.
I want to assure you
that the call
to put sergeant Jeffords
back in the field
wasn't a spur-of-the-moment,
impulse decision.
It's been in the works
for a few months now.
Terry said
it just happened.
I think you two need to get
your stories straight.
Perhaps I should
stop talking to your wife.
That's a good call.
Captain.
Sharon.
I'm so happy
to be out of that dress.
It was weirdly hot.
Oh, yeah,
it's probably because
it was a cotton
and plastic blend.
But not to worry.
We're gonna
catch these guys
and get back to the worst
date of your life.
No.
Nothing will
ever be worse
than the date I had
with my aunt's dentist.
You should try
some of this.
Okay.
Oh. Okay. Hold on.
Hmm?
Yeah, dessert
is out of the question.
What was your
worst date ever?
I think it's, like,
a 50-way tie.
The last lady I went out with
burst into tears
when I told her
I was a Gemini.
Wow.
Hey, those people
left that door open.
I bet there's a better vantage
point from the roof.
Mmm, and I bet it doesn't
smell like old cheese.
Okay, that's hurtful.
Shall we?
Yeah.
So what else
don't I know?
You cooking meth?
You breaking bad?
How many phones
do you have?
I'm sorry,
I need to clarify
something
I said earlier.
Sergeant Jeffords
was correct
when he said
that his choice to go back
in the field that night
was an impulse decision.
He didn't even take the time
to stop and gear up, so...
What?
So...
You didn't have
your vest on?
Oh, no.
Oh, goodness.
I shouldn't
have said that.
I feel I may
have made things worse.
Wait.
I can fix this, Ray.
Now is not the time, Boyle.
Hush!
I want to hear this.
Boyle, let's not make big...
Hush.
Truth time.
We love your husband.
He's a great cop.
We will do anything
to protect him.
And you have incredibly
attractive hands.
And you, what the hell
are you doing,
lying to your wife?
Unless you want to
end up moving
into my ex-wife's new
boyfriend's basement with me,
you better man up.
Don't you ever
keep anything
from this
beautiful woman again.
Seriously,
you are beautiful.
Oh.
If he ever lies to you again,
you can call me.
I'm sorry, honey.
I just didn't
want you to worry.
Baby, I am always
gonna worry about you.
But if you feel
like you're ready,
then get your ass
back in the field.
But if you ever keep
anything from me again,
I will leave you
for this short, earnest man
and his ex-wife's new
boyfriend's apartment.
I know you're kidding,
but Hercules is actually
a very good landlord.
Sometimes, when they go
on nice vacations,
I'm allowed
to use the hot tub.
Man, I don't know
how Batman does it.
It is super scary
up here.
Hey, will you grab
the binoculars?
They're in
my stakeout bag.
Your stakeout bag
is 98% nuts.
I get snacky.
Besides,
nuts are super healthy.
They're, like, 0% fat.
Jake, that's not
true at all.
It's actually
the opposite.
What?
That nut vendor lied to me.
I think a pigeon
just flew out of your car.
Yeah.
The windows
don't exactly roll up.
The car's
a piece of crap.
Why do you love it
so much?
You really
want to know?
I was two days out of
the academy, super nervous.
Saw this guy
run out of a bodega,
clutching
a bunch of cash.
So I pursued him
on foot, 11 blocks.
Finally catch him,
cuff him,
throw him up against
that car.
Turned out there was a for sale
sign in the window,
and, it being the best day
of my life, I bought it.
Thus began the debt.
Crushing debt.
Yeah, you do know me.
Nut?
Only if you throw it.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
Nice.
You ready?
Uh-huh.
What are you doing?
Trying to catch it
in your nose?
I got it,
I got it, I got it.
It's Holt.
Keep practicing.
Okay.
Peralta.
Oh, good news, Peralta.
I found someone
from the night shift
to relieve you
on your stakeout.
Ooh.
Still make Times Square.
Um...
You know, Captain,
hold off on the relief team.
We're already here.
Plus I'm curious
to see what happens.
Okay, it's your call.
All right.
What did Holt want?
Just checking in.
How you doing?
Any progress?
Yep.
Watch.
The key is volume.
I see that.
So be honest.
If you'd won the bet,
were you really
gonna destroy my car?
No.
I was gonna drive it.
So I could learn stick.
You wouldn't.
I would.
Would've been, like,
No.
No!
Hey, hey!
There's our guys.
What's the play here?
Just follow my lead.
Give me the ring.
Now give me some nuts.
I'm snacky.
All right, fine,
darling.
I'll ask him.
Will that make you happy?
Excuse me, sir.
We're kind of busye.
Yeah, my girlfriend,
here, thinks we're lost.
No, I know we're lost.
I think he's an idiot.
Idiot?
You know why
we're out here
in the middle
of the night, Susan?
I was gonna
propose to you.
On the Brooklyn bridge,
where we met.
Brooklyn bridge?
We met on
the Manhattan bridge.
You know what?
This is over.
Say good-bye to the ring
and everything it represents.
You son of a bitch!
Hey, hey.
Stop yelling
hey, no one talks to Susan
like that.
And you know what else? On the ground!
NYPD! NYPD!
You're under arrest.
Nice work.
You too.
I'm sad y'all
are arresting me,
but I gotta say,
I'm glad you're back together.
Hey.
I need to talk to you.
Oh.
It's happening?
Remember when I took those
bus for you?
Okay, let's do this.
I think you're sweet...
I didn't know
it was you.
When I jumped in front
of those bullets,
I didn't know
who I was protecting.
I just saw a gun
and an NYPD vest,
and so
I dove on instinct.
You've been extra nice
to me
because you thought
I'd risked my life for you.
But I only did
what every good cop would do.
When you finally
go out with me, and you will,
it'll be because
I do things
that only Charles Boyle
would do.
Um, actually,
I have a coat in here.
It's, uh... it's,
like... actually, I see it.
It's, like... it's blue... it's,
like, right...
Excellent job on the stakeout
last night.
I'm glad to see you two
still work well together
despite that
ridiculous bet.
Thanks.
Me too.
And I appreciate your turning
down the relief team.
I'm not sure
they could've made that bust.
Yeah.
Right.
The relief team.
So... sorry you lost so much
money last night.
Guess you can add it
to your list of bad dates.
Nah, it still goes on
the good date list.
You know, 'cause we caught
the bad guys.
That's very mature
of you.
Well,
I am very mature man.
Package for Amy Santiago.
That's me.
Special delivery from
Jake Peralta to say,
"thanks for last night."
Oh, no.
I forgot to cancel.
♪ Here I am
Cancel what?
Sir, you don't have to...
Okay.
All right, so...
Uhh... eugh!
Okay, no, no,
no, no, no.
All right, stepping in,
stepping in.
I'll take this bullet
for you.
Ugh. Hitchcock,
what are you doing?
I thought... aren't
we all gonna... no?
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.addic7ed.com/
www.tvsubtitles.net